誰かが訪うてた
Somebody asked a question once
この世の善と惡の差
About the difference between good and evil –
答えは求めていない
I'm not looking for the answer.
そんな世界の常
Scandal and reputation are blended together
醜聞と外聞を混ぜて
and a shallow ‘virtue' is handed down.
伝わる薄っぺらな善
Such is the state of this world.
世の中にはちょっと飽き飽きしていた
I've been a bit bored with the world lately.
誰もやらぬのなら　私がやってやろう
If no-one's gonna do it, then I'll do it!
これが正義と言う名の一太刀さ
Hah! My sword's strokes bear the name of justice.
迷う人も　謀る詮無き人も
Those who are lost, and those who aren't worth duping…
まとめて全てを　打ち払い百花繚乱
I'll brush them aside, all at once, like countless flowers.
終ぞ知れずに
They'll never be aware of it
心に雲のかからぬよう
I'll do it so their hearts won't be clouded over
鞘を投げ捨て
I throw my scabbard away.
この身一つ正義の名の元に
With this body alone, I make my way to the name of ‘Justice.'
この世に蔓延る　善惡混じりの弁は
This world is infested by petals of good and evil mixed together
路肩の屑と変わらぬ
Though they're identical to rubbish on the side of the road…
嗚呼　なんと人の世は
Ahh, don't you think
とてもとても　住みにくいのだろうか
That the human world is a dreadfully difficult place to live in?
綺麗な空気がただ欲しくなる
I find myself just wanting to breathe clean air…
見せ掛けの善意
They pretend to have a virtuous mind
張りぼての相槌に
With their paper mache signs of comprehension
鉄槌下すだなんて
After all, dealing a crushing blow
杜撰なモノだって
Would be such a sloppy thing to do…
道を踏み外した
All those people, with their doubts
迷い多き人を
Have strayed from the path
正した正義が　迷い持ってはならない
Thou shalt not hold doubts – that is correct justice.
離れ残心
I am separated from my alertness
むき身の感情その身に受け
As my body receives this feeling of bareness.
映る刃に仏の顔を映し出してる
Buddha's face is reflected upon my blade…
人は恋すると強くなると言う
They say when you love someone, you become stronger…
人は信じる強さがあると言う
They say that believing in other people is a form of strength, too…
何故に人を守るのだろう
But I wonder, why do you protect other people?
映る刃に問い掛ける
I ask my blade, reflected before me.
人は平気で嘘をつくと言う
They say that humans tell lies without remorse.
迷い切り捨て御免
I lose control, and cut and leave…
残山斬惨懺
Slash! Slash! Slash! Slash! Slash!
心無く語る騙る人の多き事
All of those people who thoughtlessly talk and lie to others…
そんな言葉に　踊らされ有象無象
And the masses, who are made to dance through phrases such as:
誰か信じて
Put your trust in others,
裏切られ傷つくことはない
And they will never betray you or harm you.
そんな手合いは刃の錆だ
Hah! Those kinds of people… are rust on my blade!
そして　惡を討ち善の御首級挙げる
Thus, I defeat evil, and raise the severed head of virtue.
真の善行は全てを涅槃へ誘う
True benevolence is beckoning all to Nirvana.
最大のまごころで
With the greatest devotion,
最愛の人を斬る
I kill my beloved.
抜き身の刃は　この世の惡を映した
The evil of the world was reflected on my drawn sword.
私の顔を映し出していた
So, too, was my face